UPDATED ANSWERS 1/24

> 1. In your own words, explain what clean code is and why it is important.

There are a lot of elements that go into clean code and it is important for a variety of reasons.
On the macro level clean code is about creating code that is easily readable when you or someone else
is parcing it. Naming is an important part of this. You want variables and functions that have
descriptive names instread of just "x" and "y" so you know what part of the code is being affected. 
Another element is Don't Repeat Yourself, the principel that you should code that can be repeated in
different sections instead of making new code for each task. This keeps your code clean and clutter
free. Finally, an element that goes into clean code is the single responsability princpel. With this,
you wnat to make sure code lives in specific components that can be accessed on a global level. All
of these things go together to create easier to read code that changes and fixes can be made by you 
or someone else.


> 2. Read this article about Toyota and their use of bad code. 
Although you may not yet understand all of the topics discussed, think about another commonly 
used object that relies on computers and explain what would happen if the code was not created to 
an acceptable standard.

Another commonly used object that relies on computers are commuter trains. These trains (or subways)
use computer systems to know how fast to go and when to slow down near stations. When there are errors
in this code it can cause accidents such as derailments or crashes with other trains. It is important
that the code is clean so tZZZhese accidents can be avoided

> 3. Would you consider the following to be clean code? Explain why or why not. If not, refactor the code.

This is not clean because it is not nested properly and the variables are not descriptive. 
This is what it looks like when it's fixed.

FUNCTION do(temp, tempType)               
	IF tempType = "F" THEN              
		SET convertedTemp to (temp−32) * (5/9)       
			PRINT convertedTemp                      
	ELSE IF tempType = "C" THEN          
		SET convertedTemp to temp * 1.8000 + 32.00   
			PRINT convertedTemp                       
	END IF
END FUNCTION

> 4. Would you consider the following to be clean code? Explain why or why not. If not, refactor the code.

This code is clean. It is properly nested and named correctly

> 5. Using pseudocode, refactor the code for the following examples using the principles you have learned in this checkpoint.
a. The following function prints the subtotal of a customer's transaction and receives payment accordingly.

FUNCTION checkOutCustomer(subTotal, discountRate, paymentType)

   var totalDiscountTax = subTotal * discountRate + (subTotal * tax)

   IF paymentType = 'CASH' THEN
       CALL checkOutCustomer RETURNING amount
       PRINT "Change due: " + amount - totalDiscountTax
   ELSE IF paymentType = 'CREDIT CARD' THEN
       CALL checkOutCustomer RETURNING amount
       PRINT "Your credit card has been charged: " + totalDiscountTax
   END IF
END FUNCTION

> b. The following function checks out a book if there are no issues with the guest's account.

FUNCTION checkoutBook(book, guest)
	IF guest.accountActive && (!guest.hasOverdueBooks) && guest.outstandingFees = 0 THEN
           APPEND book to guest.books
           	SET book.status to "Checked Out"
          		 PRINT "Your books have been issued."
 	ELSE
    		PRINT "Unable to check out book."
 	END IF
END FUNCTION

> c.  The following class is a code snippet that should support the transactions a customer can perform at an ATM.

CLASS BankAccountBalance

 FUNCTION displayBalance
    PRINT balance
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION deposit(amount)
    SET balance to balance + amount
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION withdraw(amount)
     IF balance > amount THEN
       SET balance to balance - amount
     END
 END FUNCTION

CLASS membershipStatus

 FUNCTION creditCardOffer
     IF NOT(customer.hasCreditCard) THEN
         CALL offerCreditCard
     END
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION checkStatus
     IF NOT(customer.hasCheckingAccount) THEN
         CALL offerCheckingAccount
     END
 END FUNCTION

 ....
 ....
 ....

END

> 6. Square Given an array of integers, find out whether the sum of the integers is a 
perfect square. If it is a perfect square, return the square root, otherwise return the sum.

var sum = [1, 2, 1].reduce(add, 0);

function add(a, b){
    return a + b;
}

function isSquare(sum){
    return Math.sqrt(sum) % 1 === 0
}

console.log(sum);

console.log(isSquare(sum));

> 7. Duplicate Given an array of integers, find out whether the array contains any duplicate 
elements. The function should return true if any value appears at least twice in the array, 
and false if every element is distinct.

var numbers = [1, 2, 3, 4, 4]

var duplicateCheck = function(numList) {
    for(var i = 0; i <= numList.length; i++) {
        for(var dupeCheck = i; dupeCheck <= numList.length; dupeCheck++) {
            if(i != dupeCheck && numList[i] == numList[dupeCheck]) {
                return true;
            }
        }
    }
    return false;
}

console.log(duplicateCheck(numbers))
